Finding Aid for the Collection of Turkish Manuscripts LSC.0896
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Title (Romanized): Gülzâr-i ma'nevi Uniform title: Gülzâr-i ma'nevi Title (English): The spiritual rose-field Alternative titles: ????? ?????, Gulzar-i mánavi, Date: 1642 October; Manuscript number: 33; 128 leaves: paper; 286 x 202 mm. bound to 283 x 190 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, blind-stamped, with marble paste-downs, and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words verses in red, enclosed in red borders. (Box 11)
  A mystical poem in Turkish on various scriptural passages. The original date of composition was 1453 (127a).
- Title (Romanized): Muhammediye Uniform title: Muhammediye Title (English): [The book] of Mu?ammad Alternative titles: ??????? ????????, al-Risalah al- Mu?amadiyah, Date: 1744; Manuscript number: 34; 266 leaves: paper; 313 x 195 mm. bound to 313 x 200 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, inlaid, with gilt borders, and blue marble paste-downs; damaged. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words verses in red, enclosed in gilt and black borders; illumination on 1b. (Box 12)
  Islam: doctrine and belief regarding the world, God, prophets, angels, signs of judgment day, etc. A verse translation into Turkish of the author's Magharib al-zaman, translated also by his brother into Turkish prose (Envar ül-âsikîn. See mss. 11 above). The verse translation was completed in August 1449 (263a).
- Title (Romanized): Fütûhu'l-mücahidin li-tervih-i kulûbi'l- müsâhidiin Uniform title: Nefehâtü'l-üns min hadarâti'l-kuds Title (English): The conquests of the holy warriors for the encouragement of the hearts of witnesses Alternative titles: ???? ????????? ?????? ???? ?????????, Futu? al- mujahidin li tarwi? qulub al-mushahidin, Date: 1575; Manuscript number: 35; Layout: 27 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, inlaid, with fore-edge flap; damaged. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, occasional words in red; marginalia; water damage. (Box 12)
  This is the Turkish translation of Jami's (1414-1492) biography of Sufis entitled Nafa?at al-uns min ha?arat al-quds. The Turkish translation was undertaken in 1521 in commemoration of a victory of Sultan Süleyman the Magnificent in Hungary.
- Title (Romanized): Umdetü'l-Islam Title (English): The pillar of Islam Alternative titles: ???? ??????, 'Imad al-Islam, 'Umdat al-Islam, Date: 1602 December; Manuscript number: 36; 260 leaves: paper; 300 x 195 mm. bound to 300 x 196 mm.; Layout: 23 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, with fore-edge flap; damaged. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; considerable water damage; at least one leaf missing from the beginning and first leaf damaged. (Box 13)
- Title (Romanized): Mesa'irü's-su'ara [hulâsas?] Title (English): [The abridgement] of the stations of the poets Alternative titles: Masha'ir al-shúara, Date: [19--]; Manuscript number: 37; 58 leaves: paper; 330 x 240 mm. bound to 333 x 248 mm.; Layout: Average 36 lines of text per page. Script: Riqa. Binding: Brown leather with marble paste-downs. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, number given to each author in red pencil; incomplete table of contents and supplied title on front end-papers. (Box 14)
  This is an abridgement of the sixteenth- century biography of Ottoman poets written by Âs?k Çelebi, 1520- 1572.
- Title (Romanized): Takvim Uniform title: Takvim üt-tevarih li-Kâtib Çelebi Title (English): Calendar Alternative titles: Taqwim? ?????, Date: Before 1812; Manuscript number: 38; 84 leaves: paper; 289 x 190 mm. bound to 289 x 191 mm.; Layout: Average 17/28 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown paper over boards with leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, enclosed in red and blue borders; charts and tables; illumination on 1b; water damage. (Box 14)
- Title (Romanized): Risale-i nuriye Title (English): The luminosity treatise Alternative titles: ????? ?????, Risalah-i nuriyah, Date: [19--]; Manuscript number: 39; 15 leaves: paper; 340 x 233 mm. bound to 343 x 241 mm.; Layout: 29 lines of text per page. Script: Riqa. Binding: Red and green marble paper. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink; leaf one damaged. (Box 14)
  Sufism: short treatise on the soul and gnosis.
- Title (Romanized): Vak'a-i Zagra Uniform title: Tarihçe-i vak'a-i Zagra Title (English): The battle of Zagra Alternative titles: ???? ????, Vaqah-i Zaghrah, Waqah Zaghrah, Date: [188-]; Manuscript number: 40; 44 leaves: paper; 282 x 213 mm. bound to 291 x 216 mm.; Layout: 23 lines of text per page. Script: Riqa. Binding: Red paper over borads. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, some headings in gold; leaf one damaged. (Box 14)
  A brief history in Ottoman Turkish of the battle of Zagra during the Russo-Turkish wars by an author who was the native of the town. A shorter title follows this.
- Title (Romanized): Âdap-i menazil Title (English): Manners of the household Alternative titles: ???? ?????, Adab-i manazil, Date: [16--]?; Manuscript number: 41; 44 leaves: paper; 251 x 155 mm. bound to 251 x 162 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Black leather, inlaid, gilt borders, and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, some headings in gold; leaf one damaged. (Box 14)
  Identity of the author derived from the Türkiye Diyanet Vakf? Islâm ansiklopedisi.
  The author writes that he compiled a number of authorities and translated them into Turkish for the religious guidance of a number of ladies who used to refer to him. It covers issues such as the legal rights of wives, the life-story of the daughter of the prophet, rights of parents over children, rights of women over men, and that of men over women, etc.
- Title (Romanized): Nakd-i hât?r Title (English): Money for the memory Alternative titles: ??? ????, Naqd-i kha?ir, Naqd al-kha?ir, Naqd al-khawa?ir, Date: 1809; Manuscript number: 42; 205 leaves: paper; 237 x 162 mm. bound to 237 x 168 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Burgundy leather, blind-stamped, with yellow paste-downs, and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, enclosed in red borders; 1b illuminated; leaf one damaged. (Box 15)
  A Turkish commentary on the Koranic chapter 18 (the cave), but also containing many stories about Moses, originally begun 1594 under the Ottoman Sultan Murad III but then dedicated (4b) to Mehmet III (1595-1603) after the former's death.
- Title (Romanized): Umdetü'l-Islam Title (English): [The pillar of Islam] Alternative titles: ???? ??????, 'Imad al-Islam, 'Umdat al-Islam, Date: No date; Manuscript number: 43; 99 leaves: paper; 293 x 198 mm. bound to 287 x 209 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Yellow paper. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, water damage; leaves from the beginning missing, leaves at the end badly damaged. (Box 15)
- Title (Romanized): [Tercüme-i] Vefayatü'l-âyan Uniform title: Tercüme-yi Vefayat ül-âyan li-bin Khallikan Title (English): The translation of the Obituaries of notables Alternative titles: ????? ??????, Wafayat al-áyan., Date: 1715; Manuscript number: 44; 209 leaves: paper; 310 x 169 mm.; Layout: 29 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: missing. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, enclosed in red borders; 1b illuminated; water damage; leaves are badly damaged; text on 1b and 2a barely legible; final leaf separated. (Box 15)
  This is a Turkish translation of Ibn Khallikan's (1211-1282) biography of Muslim notables. The translation was undertaken in 1676 and was dedicated to a vizier named Mustafa Pasa which must be Merzifonlu Kara Mustafa Pasa who served as vizier from 167683. Manuscript in several hands.
- Title (Romanized): Acay?p-i mahlûkat Title (English): Wonders of creation Alternative titles: ????? ???????, Acay?p-i mahlûkat ve garay?p-i mevcudat, 'Ajayib-i makhluqat,' Aja'ib makhluqat, Date: [17--]?; Manuscript number: 45; 102 leaves: paper; 307 x 174 mm. bound to 303 x 187 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, blind-stamped, gilt edges; another front board supplied later; very badly damaged. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink; illustrations; leaves torn and damaged. (Box 16)
  A composition about the strange things in the universe dedicated to Sultan Osman II (1618-1622) son of Sultan Ahmet I (1603- 1617).
- Title (Romanized): [Tercüme-i] Tuhfetu'l-ahbap fi's-sülûk ila tarik Title (English): [The translation of] the Gift of the lovers who have set out upon the path Alternative titles: ?????] ???? ?????? ?? ?????? ??? ????], Tu?fat al-a?bab fi al-suluk ilá ?ariq, Date: 1884 March; Manuscript number: 46; 92 leaves: paper; 274 x 179 mm. bound to 274 x 183 mm.; Layout: 15 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Pink marble over boards with fore-edge flap and red leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, occasional phrases in red, enclosed in black borders; some pages stuck together. (Box 16)
  Author identified as Eyyub b. Halil in Türkiye Diyanet Vakf? Islâm ansiklopedisi, and as Hâc Abdullah Eyyubî in the manuscript.
  Sufism. The first title is a translation into Turkish of an Arabic original called Tu?fat al-a?bab fi al-suluk ilá ?ariq written by an author named Shaykh A?mad ?arabizuni (Trabzoni). This book was itself an exposition on another book called Silsilat al-dhahab written by Shaykh Mu?ammad Murad al-Bukhari.
- Title (Romanized): Sübhat'ul-ahbar Title (English): Glory of reports Alternative titles: Sub?at al-akhbar, Date: [16--]?; Manuscript number: 47; 50 leaves: paper; 292 x 203 mm. bound to 288 x 202 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Green paper over boards with brown leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and numbers in red, illustrations on 1b-34a. (Box 16)
  Ottoman history. The main title is a Turkish translation of a Persian original. This is a genealogy of kings and prophets including the Ottoman House. The text is dedicated to Sultan Süleyman the Magnificent (r. 1520- 1566). However, the list of Ottoman sultans is written up to the enthronement of Selim II in 1566 and is abruptly ended. This title spans leaves 36b-50b but is incomplete and only contains one leaf from the family tree of the Mamluk sultanate of Egypt and the leaves covering the Ottoman House up to Selim II. The second title is a chart of genealogy of kings and prophets extracted from the history of Nisanc? (see mss. 48 below). It culminates in the name of Murad IV (r. 1623 to 1640 ). However, a second hand has added in the margin a list of the noteworthy events of his reign. Then, on the following list, later and less elaborate illustrations of various sultans has been added to continue the chronology up to the reign of Sultan Mahmud II (180839) ).
- Title (Romanized): Mine't-tevarih-i Nisanc? Title (English): From Nisanc?'s histories Alternative titles: ?? ???????? ??????, Min al-tawarikh Nishanji, Date: 1754 April; Manuscript number: 48; 16 leaves: paper; 280 x 204 mm.; Layout: 5 lines of illustrations per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Faded marble paper on boards. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, names in red circles. (Box 16)
  A note on 1b writes that the charts were copied from the histories of Nisanc? Mehmed Pasa (16th century). The most elaborate of all illustrations is for Süleyman the Magnificent (r. 1520-1566). However, the last illustration is for the name of Murad IV (r. 1623 to 1640 ). The text is incomplete and is missing several leaves from the beginning.
- Title (Romanized): Tefsir-i Hüseyn Vaiz Tercümesi Title (English): Translation of the exegesis of ?usayn Va'i? Alternative titles: ????? ???? ???? ???????, Date: [16--]; Manuscript number: 49; 279 leaves: paper; 316 x 215 mm. bound to 327 x 226 mm.; Layout: 27 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown faux Morocco. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, enclosed in red borders; 1b illuminated; some water damage. (Box 16)
  Identity of the author derived from Kâtip Çelebi's Kashf al- ?unun. He seems to be the son of the famous historian of the Ottoman empire who died in 1520.
  This is the Turkish translation of a Persian-language exegesis of the Koran by ?usayn Vai? Kashifi (d. 1504 or 5) entitled Mavahib-i aliyah. The present manuscript seems to be the second of two volumes and contains the last few verses of Chapter 18 of the Koran (Mary) to the end.
- Title (Romanized): Ciltu's-salis min siyeri'n-nebi Title (English): Volume three of the life of the prophet Alternative titles: ??? ?????? ?? ??? ?????, Jild [sic] al- thalith min siyar al-nabiy, Date: 1569 March; Manuscript number: 50; 176 leaves: paper; 255 x 157 mm. bound to 253 x 157 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Orange Morocco with black leather around the edges; fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red. (Box 17)
  This is a Turkish translation of Ibn Is?aq's biography of the prophet Mu?ammad generally known as Sirat al-Nabi or al-Sirah al- Nabawiyah.
- Title (Romanized): [Mesáirü's-súara] Uniform title: Mesair üs-súara, or, Te?kere of As?? Çelebi Title (English): [Stations of the poets] Alternative titles: ????? ??????, Masha'ir al-shúara, Date: 1578 January; Manuscript number: 51; 249 leaves: paper; 250 x 157 mm. bound to 237 x 157 mm.; Layout: 25 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Faux blue Morocco supplied later. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, enclosed in red borders, poets names in margins in red circles; several leaves separated. (Box 17)
  As?k Çelebi's comprehensive biography of Ottoman poets.
- Title (Romanized): Riyazü'r-rahme Title (English): Gardens of forgiveness Alternative titles: ???? ??????, Riya? al-ra?mah, Date: 1638 February; Manuscript number: 52; 71 leaves: paper; 285 x 154 mm. bound to 284 x 155 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Purple paper over boards with burgundy leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; water damage; stains; extensive editing; marginalia. (Box 17)
  A composition in Turkish on fasting, pilgrimage, etc. The author says that he drew his information from a book called Raw?at al-wai?in, presumably the work of Shiite biography by Fattal.
- Title (Romanized): [Tercüme-i mukaddeme-i Ibn Haldun] Uniform title: Tercüme-yi Mukaddeme-yi Ibn Haldun Title (English): [The translation of Ibn Khaldun's Muqaddimah] Alternative titles: [Tarjumah-i Muqaddimah-i Ibn Khaldun], [Tarjumat al-Muqaddimah Ibn Khaldun], Date: [17--]; Manuscript number: 53; 639 leaves: paper; 242 x 173 mm. bound to 241 x 174 mm.; Layout: 27 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Green leather with brown leather stripe around the edges; fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, few marked words and underlining in red; enclosed in red borders; table of contents on ff. 1b-10a. (Box 18)
  This is a translation of the preface to Ibn Khaldun's history, completed by Pirizade in 1730 (15b) and dedicated to Sultan Mahmud I (r. 1730-1754).
- Title (Romanized): Tezkeretü'l-evliya Uniform title: Tezkiretü'l-evliyâ Title (English): Remembrance of [Sufi] masters Alternative titles: ????? ??????, Tadhkirat al-awlya', Date: 1430 June; Manuscript number: 54; 267 leaves: paper; 270 x 195 mm. bound to 270 x 200 mm.; Layout: 15 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown paper over boards with brown leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; spine cracking in the middle. (Box 18)
  The author of this translation is other than Sinan Pasa (1440-1486), whose Turkish translation is more well-known and is noticed in Kâtip Çelebi's Kashf al- ?unun.
  This is a very early Ottoman translation of the biography of Sufi masters by Farid al-Din A??ar completed, or copied, during the reign of the Ottoman Sultan Murat II. A number of short treatises are appended to 1a-16b.
- Title (Romanized): Hadikatü's-süedâ Uniform title: Hadikatü's-sü'eda Title (English): Garden of the blessed folks Alternative titles: ????? ??????, ?adiqat al-súada, Date: 1678; Manuscript number: 55; 191 leaves: paper; 284 x 186 mm. bound to 282 x 189 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Brown leather, blind-stamped, with fore-edge flap; damaged. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red; water damage. (Box 18)
  Fuzulî's account of the martyrdom of the third Shiite imam ?usayn ibn Ali. The text is mainly a translation of the Persian-language Raw?at al-shuhada' by the Timurid author ?usayn Vai? Kashifi (d. 1504 or 5.)
- Title (Romanized): Umdetü'l-Islam Title (English): The pillar of Islam Alternative titles: ???? ??????, Imad al-Islam, Umdat al-Islam, Date: 1660 June; Manuscript number: 56; 165 leaves: paper; 292 x 190 mm. bound to 292 x 200 mm.; Layout: 20 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, blind-stamped, torn and frayed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red, enclosed in red borders; 1a illuminated; water damage. (Box 19)
- Title (Romanized): [Tercüme-i Tarih-i Tabari] Title (English): [Translation of ?abari's history] Alternative titles: ??? ?????? ????, Kisas-i tevârih-i Tabari, Date: [15--]?; Manuscript number: 57; 234 leaves: paper; 273 x 175 mm. bound to 278 x 192 mm.; Layout: 23 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Red cloth over boards with black leather stripe over spine; separated from the manuscript. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red; leaves missing from the beginning. (Box 19)
  This is a translation of the history of ?abari into Ottoman Turkish. The author seems to have used the older Persian translation of ?abari's Arabic original.
- Title (Romanized): [Tercüme-i Tarih-i Tabari] Title (English): [Translation of ?abari's history] Alternative titles: ??? ?????? ????, Kisas-i tevârih-i Tabari, Date: 1570 April; Manuscript number: 58; 279 leaves: paper; 283 x 195 mm. bound to 292 x 190 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Brown leather, blind-stamped, with fore-edge flap; torn, frayed, and water-damaged. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red, enclosed in red borders; 1a illuminated; pages separated; water damage. (Box 20)
  This is a translation of the history of ?abari into Ottoman Turkish. The author seems to have used the older Persian translation of ?abari's Arabic original. The statements in Kâtip Çelebi's Kashf al-?unun that the Turkish translation enjoyed popularity among "the common people of Rum (Anatolia)" is confirmed by the home town of the Scribe--i.e. Konya in Central Anatolia.
- Title (Romanized): Tercüme-i Tefsir-i Tibyan Uniform title: Tefsir-i Tibyan ve Tefsir-i Mevakip Title (English): Translation of the exegesis of exposition Alternative titles: ????? ????? ?????, Date: [17--]?; Manuscript number: 59; 327 leaves: paper; 317 x 200 mm. bound to 316 x 200 mm.; Layout: 35 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Green cloth over boards with yellow paste-downs. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red, enclosed in red borders; 1a illuminated. (Box 20)
  Volume 1 of a Koranic exegesis dedicated to Minkarizade Yahya Efendi(1609-1678) and the Ottoman Sultan Mehmet IV (r. 164887). Several scribes.
- Title (Romanized): Maariçü'n-nübüvve Uniform title: Maariç ün-nübüvve Title (English): The ascensions of prophet-hood Alternative titles: ????? ??????, Date: [15--]?; Manuscript number: 60; 251 leaves: paper; 296 x 186 mm. bound to 293 x 192 mm.; Layout: 25 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black and yellow marble paper over boards with fore-edge flap and purple paste-downs. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red; 1a added later and illuminated. (Box 21)
  The author calls himself Mustafa b. Celal and has dedicated the work to Süleyman the Magnificent in the city of Edirne in 1551 (2b).
  Stories of the life of the prophet Mu?ammad, emphasizing his ascension to heaven. The text is based on Múin al-Din Farahi's Máarif al-nubuwwah fi madarij al-futuwwah. As Kâtip Çeleb has noted, the present title is different from a second (and later) Turkish translation of this text by Alt?parmak Mehmet (d. 1623).
- Title (Romanized): [Irsâdü'l-mürid ile'l-murad fi tercümet-i Mirsâdi'l-ibâd] Title (English): [Guiding the seeker towards what is desired by translating The path of bondsmen], Date: [15--]?; Manuscript number: 61; 191 leaves: paper; 260 x 170 mm. bound to 260 x 175 mm.; Layout: 15 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, torn, damaged, and separated. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red, enclosed in red borders; illuminated throughout; leaves missing.
  Ottoman Turkish translation of Najm al-Din Razi's (d. 1256 or 7) Mir?ad al-ibad min al-mabdá ilá al- máad. Completed in 1419 during the reign of Murad II.
- Title (Romanized): Âdap-i menazil Title (English): Manners of the household Alternative titles: ???? ?????, Date: 1730; Manuscript number: 62; 222 leaves: paper; 292 x 195 mm. bound to 292 x 204 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Burgundy leather, inlaid, with yellow paste-downs and flap; inscribed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red, enclosed in red borders; marginalia. (Box 22)
- Title (Romanized): [Mevaiz] Title (English): [Exhortations], Date: Before 1779; Manuscript number: 63; 204 leaves: paper; 289 x 187 mm. bound to 287 x 272 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather with stripe over spine; water damage. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red; leaves missing from the beginning; water-damaged and separated; illustration on 68a. (Box 22)
  In possession of Süleyman Efendi in 1779 (his note on front end- paper).
  Book on religious topics such as sinfulness, the need for promoting virtue and preventing vice, remorse, and the prayers of Moses. Interspersed with Koranic verses.
- Title (Romanized): Lehcetü'l-lugât Uniform title: Lehcetü'l-lugât Title (English): Dictionary of words Alternative titles: ???? ??????, Date: [17--]; Manuscript number: 64; 796 leaves: paper; 310 x 175 mm. bound to 310 x 169 mm.; Layout: 25 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Burgundy leather, inlaid, with green marble paste-downs, gilt edges and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red, enclosed in red borders; 1b illuminated. (Box 23)
  A Turkish-Arabic-Persian dictionary with pronunciation guides.
- Title (Romanized): Muhammediye Uniform title: Muhammediye Title (English): [The book] of Muhammad Alternative titles: ??????? ????????, Date: [17--]?; Manuscript number: 65; 266 leaves: paper; 285 x 180 mm. bound to 281 x 192 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, blind-stamped, with green cloth around the edges, water damage. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red, enclosed in red borders; 1b illuminated. (Box 24)